>> First, you want to understand the business goals.
首先 你要理解业务目标
If you're not making money, if you're not responding to where the business
如果不能赚钱 不能支持所需的业务增长
needs to grow and to the culture that the business is promoting,
不能符合业务宣传的文化
then the solution might be the wrong one.
解决方案就可能是错误的
Second, you want to understand engineering.
第二 你要理解工程技术
The technologies, which makes the ideas come to life.
是技术把创意带进现实
So without understanding where the technology's at and
如果你不了解当前的技术水平
what the team is able to deliver, it kind of doesn't matter.
这个团队能够达成怎样的结果 基本上就毫无意义了
That's it.
是这样的
So we covered the business perspective and then we covered the technology.
我们已经谈到了业务和技术两个方面
What's missing?
缺少了什么？
What do you think is the third perspective?
你认为第三个角度是什么？
>> The users?
用户？
>> That's right.
是的
If there's something that's important in design solution, it is who it is for.
是的 这对设计解决方案是非常重要的 你为谁设计
The designers and the whole team need to understand who are the potential users
设计师和整个团队需要理解谁是潜在用户
and what are their needs?
他们的需求是什么？
When you circle problem in this manner and you look at it from all
当你用这种方式全面地看到这个问题
perspectives, business, technology, design, you're creating a more
从多个角度来看 业务、技术、设计 你就能创造更整体性的方法
holistic approach, so that the solutions that come have wisdom to them.
解决方案会更具智慧
That they're not rushed, that they're better targeted.
不会仓促了事 而会更好地针对问题
>> And what would you say is the most important thing in this stage?
你觉得这个阶段最重要的是什么？
>> I think in this stage, it's important to hear different perspectives.
我觉得在这个阶段中 你一定要听取不同角度的意见
If you are over focusing on one and not the other,
如果你太多关注某一个角度而忽视了其他
you might have a solution that's lopsided.
你的解决方案可能会不平衡
So in sprint, we try to be balanced in the beginning and hear from everyone
所以在冲刺中 我们在一开始要学着平衡
who'll be involved in making the product or who'll be involved in approving it.
并听取所有参与或批准产品制作的人的意见
If you're in a large company,
如果你是个大公司
this may be the director of the product and the director of engineering.
可能是产品总监和工程总监
They represent the business and the technology.
他们代表业务和技术
Similarly, the user researchers or the marketing and sales teams.
同样 用户研究员或者是市场营销和销售团队也是如此
Now, if you're in a startup,
那 如果你是个创业公司
you might not have a person representing every single perspective.
你可能没有代表单个角度的人员
>> You could be the single person who represents everything.
你可能是一个人代表所有角度
>> You could be the three things, right?
你可以代表这三个方面 对吧？
>> Right.
是的
>> In a startup, you often are wearing all these different hats.
在创业公司里 你经常需要扮演不同的角色
So, it's useful to consider and pause.
这时候 你需要思考并且暂停 这很有用
Even if you're one person or
即便你是一个人
even if you are small team that doesn't have diversified roles yet,
或者你的团队很小没有这么多不同的角色
what are the perspectives on this problem as looking in it from
你要从业务角度来看待这个问题的话
a business perspective, there's one set of issues that they're important.
有一系列重要的东西
Those are about the metrics, the goals, the revenue.
比如指标、目标、收益等
Looking in from a technology perspective,
如果是技术角度
there's another set of problems.
又有另一个系列的问题
That is generally, what is the code able to do?
总体来说 代码能够实现什么？
What are the features that are being developed?
要开发哪些功能？
What's available to outsource or what APIs are available to bring in?
什么可以外包出去 可以引进哪些 API？
And then from a design perspective,
然后从设计角度来说
it's about what are the user needs that you want to address?
你想要解决什么用户需求？
When you look at it from these three perspectives,
当你从三个角度来看这个问题时
even if you have a small team, you're helping people stretch their minds.
即便你只是个小团队 你也可以帮大家扩展他们的思维
They're really opening up, so that they can consider and
当他们真正地发散了思维 他们就能考虑周全
not miss out on a good idea.
不会遗漏好的创意
>> Right and what could go wrong in this stage?
好的 那这个阶段会出什么错呢？
>> Oh, that's a great question.
这个问题问得好
Often, I see teams take a very long time in this stage.
我经常会看到团队在这个阶段花费很长的时间
If the team doesn't know each other well, this may be a rare opportunity for
如果团队相互间不是很熟 这是一个难得的机会
them to start talking to each other and they're so excited to learn from each
他们可以相互聊天 并且很兴奋地相互学习
other that the stage can drag on and take two or three hours.
这样这个阶段就被拖长至两三个小时
The goal of the sprint is to understand, but then quickly move towards the other
冲刺的目标是理解 然后快速地进入下一个阶段
stages in which people are defining a strategy and starting to make things.
去确定战略然后开始制作东西
So what could go wrong is the team can spend too long in this stage.
所以可能出错的地方就是团队在这个阶段花费太长的时间
>> So they could be circling around until they understand and
他们可能一直围绕这个问题在走直到理解了这个问题
never to get to an understanding.
而不是直接去理解这个问题
>> What could go wrong is they could be like really circling.
他们容易出错的就是一直在这个问题周边打转
Another thing that could go wrong, which is actually a chance for
另外一个可能出错的就是
something to go right is that the challenge might be improperly defined.
有可能会错误定义了挑战
Sometimes people who are beginners in the art of being a sprint master,
有时候 可能有的人刚刚成为冲刺总管
approach the challenge in a very specific way.
会用很特别的方法去找到设计挑战
And when they offer to the team, they learn that actually the team has
当他们完成之后给到团队 发现团队根本有不同的需求
a different need and there's something else that's more important to solve.
有其他更重要的需要解决的东西
That is a mistake that's easier to correct in the beginning
这是在项目早期很容易犯的错
of this program and not during this phase.
而不是在项目中期
But if a sprint leader finds themself confronted with a team that says,
但如果冲刺领导发现他们和团队冲突了
we should be solving something else,
团队说我们要解决另外一些东西
it is a great opportunity to seek to understand.
这是很好地追求理解的机会
Open your ears and help your team agree on what is the right thing to do,
认真倾听 然后帮助你的团队快速地达成一致
quickly.
理解要做的正确的事是什么
>> Very cool.
很棒
So what I hear from you is that the basic of these stages to understand.
所以你告诉了我们理解这个基础阶段
To understand the business, to understand the technology and
要理解业务 理解技术
to understand your users.
理解你的用户
>> That's right.
是的